Guide to the Paul S. Seaver Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- CIV/Area One, Series 3
  - CIV Binder; correspondences and materials, Boothe Winners and Mentions, Autumn, 1 of 3, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - CIV Binder; correspondences and materials, Boothe Winners and Mentions, Autumn, 2 of 3, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - CIV Binder; correspondences and materials, Boothe Winners and Mentions, Autumn, 3 of 3, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - CIV Boothe prize for excellence in writing, 1994 November 16 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - CIV Binder; materials and correspondences; 1 of 3, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - CIV Binder; materials and correspondences; 2 of 3, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CIV Binder; materials and correspondences; 3 of 3, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - CIV Binder, miscellaneous; 1 of 3, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - CIV Binder, miscellaneous; 2 of 3, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - CIV Binder, miscellaneous; 3 of 3, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Area One, Newspapers, Stanford Daily; Stanford Campus Report, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - CIV Binder; Curriculum and Committee materials, 1 of 4, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - CIV Binder; Curriculum and Committee materials, 2 of 4, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - CIV Binder; Curriculum and Committee materials, 3 of 4, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - CIV Binder; Curriculum and Committee materials, 4 of 4, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Great Works," Report to Area One Committee, 1997 February 28 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous articles re: Western Civ issues, 1987-1990 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Encyclopedia; Western Man, Vol. 1, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Encyclopedia; Western Man, Vol. 2, Problem 1, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Encyclopedia; Western Man, Vol. 2, Problem 2, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Encyclopedia; Western Man, Vol. 2, Problem 3, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Area One Requirement Task Force charge/roster, schedule, documents, background materials, 1986-1987; Binder (Box 13)
  - Background materials (syllabi, correspondence, memos, articles, reports, etc.), 1986-1987; Binder (unlabelled) (Box 13)
  - Student Evaluations of Program, Boothe Prize materials, Departmental reports, 1991-1992; Binder (Box 13)
  - CIV 1991-92 chron file (formerly in binder), 1992 March-June (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - CIV 1991-92 chron file (formerly in binder), 1992 January-February (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - CIV 1991-92 chron file (formerly in binder), 1991 September-December (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - CIV 1991-92 chron file (formerly in binder), 1991 May-August (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - CIV/VTSS correspondence, memoranda, and other materials (formerly in binder), 1 of 4, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - CIV/VTSS correspondence, memoranda, and other materials (formerly in binder), 2 of 4, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - CIV/VTSS correspondence, memoranda, and other materials (formerly in binder), 3 of 4, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - CIV/VTSS correspondence, memoranda, and other materials (formerly in binder), 4 of 4, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Culture, Ideas and Values Program, Faculty Seminar (1 of 2), 1989 September (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Culture, Ideas and Values Program, Faculty Seminar (2 of 2), 1989 September (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Departmental and Professional Papers, Series 4
  - Department of History Department Changes materials (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History Department Business (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department Committee on Undergraduate Studies (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History Department, Various (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate Studies (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History Department (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Re. Dr. Michael Graebner's Proposal (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - British Studies Major proposed courses (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Undergraduate studies (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - British Studies Major Proposal, materials and curriculum (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate Studies, History, Requirements (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History Department Honors Program forms (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Western Culture Program (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - VTS (Values, Technology and Society) 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program in Values, Technology and Society (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate studies history (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Western Culture (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Undergraduate studies (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate History program (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History Department (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Urban Studies (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Interim Committee on Writing (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Committee to Review Undergraduate Programs, History Department (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Student Conduct Legislative Council (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Seminar Committee (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum Committee – History (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Task Force on Special Programs (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Student Conduct Legislative Council (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Subcommittee on the Freshman Year and Advising Committee On Undergraduate Studies (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Student Conduct Legislative Council, Rights and Responsibilities of Stanford Students (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Department Committee on Undergraduate Studies on Undergraduate Studies, Richard Fox Proposal (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Subcommittee on University and Department honors (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Subcommittee on Credit Review (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Studies, History Department (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - American Association of University Professors, Executive Committee (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Studies (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Foreign Studies Program (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate Studies Committee (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Undergraduate studies – HUGSA (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Studies (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate studies (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Undergraduate studies (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Committee on teaching responsibilities (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Subcommittee on great works coordinator, Winter (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Facutly Senate (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - CUS (Committee on Undergraduate Studies) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - CUS (Committee on Undergraduate Studies) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Faculty forum on switch to semester system (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - AAUP/SES (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - American Association of University Professors materials (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Experimental College Report (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Library Document Acquisition, etc (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Draft Statements on Tenure and Academic Freedom, AAUP, November (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mancall's Program in Structured Liberal Education (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Overseas Campuses (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Seminar on Social Thought and Justice (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, Summer Seminars, March (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous University Memoranda (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Faculty ‘Phonothon', September (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Overseas campuses: syllabus and CV information (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Overseas campuses: CD's and C.V.'s (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Admin Panel of University Press (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Overseas studies (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Research Grants, Travel Policy etc (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Library, Government documents; University Memoranda (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Oxford Panel (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Oxford Panel (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, Vitae, etc (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Dean and Other University Data (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Oxford Panel (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Selective Service memoranda (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Political Action Group, Peace Studies, Columbae (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Archive for Reformation of History (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Foothill College Lecture on Cromwell's English Revolution, May (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Columbae House Peace Studies (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Book Reviews of Puritan Lectureships (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Book Reviews, The Catholic Historical Review, September (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Church History (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Conference on British Studies, October (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - American Society of Church History (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers (Stanford Daily and Campus Report) I (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Newspapers (Stanford Daily and Campus Report) II (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Newspapers (Stanford Daily and Campus Report) III (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers (Stanford Daily and Campus Report) IV (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation, Law School, Susan Diamondstone, 26 December (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Recommendations (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Recommendations (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers (Stanford Daily and Campus Report) V (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper articles and clippings: Area One Western Culture requirement (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ph.D. Oral Exams (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Honors Students papers and notes (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Final Exams and subcommittee papers (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ph.D. Research Programs (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Admissions (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Freshman Advising (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Freshman Tutorial Program (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Freshman Honors Tutorials, Selection of Candidates (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Honors Tutorials, Social Activities (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Honors Tutorial Evaluation (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Honors Tutorials Planning (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Honors Tutorials, Evaluations (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Tutorial (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Honors Tutorial (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Thomas Moore College Conference, April (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - A. Larkin Kirkman, "Enrollment and Call in the Middle Temple (1551-1650): A Study of the Gentry", 13 December (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Steve Dubnoff, "The English Bishops: 1558-1647, Aspects of Their Careers", 11 September (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Jeffries Draft Case, Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Theodore W. Casteel, "Strangers in London, 1558-1618", 26 April (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation; Theodore W. Casteel, "The College and University of Arts in Nimes: An Experiment in Humanistic Education in the Age of Reform", 28 June (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Ellin Wineberg, Co-term (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Jones, Rex Franklin, Honors History Tutorial (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Steve Greene, Phil Waistler, Bev Hashimoto, History Honors Autumn (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Nimmer, David Richard, Thesis (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Jim Cameron, Humanities Thesis (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Palma Strand/Bill Lutge Freshman Honors Tutorial (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Lynn Hunt, "Sidney Sussex College, 1598-1680", Spring (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Charles F. Jennings, "An Analysis of the Trade and Social Structures of the Norwich Allen Community, 1565-1625", 23 March (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Students Thesis proposals, etc (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jack Goldstone, "State Breakdown" (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Charles L. Stinger, "The Landed Society of Hertfordshire, 1540-1680," 27 January (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Student Oral Examination Appointments and Reading Lists (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Texts and Calendars 16th and 17th Centuries (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Committee on Undergraduate Education Memos I (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Committee on Undergraduate Education Memos II (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education: Roster & Charge (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education: Committee Reports (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education: Social Thought & Justice (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education: Freshman-Sophomore Seminars (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education: Ancient Africa (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education: Learning Assistance Center (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Steven Dubnoff, "Religion and University Enrollments in England 1560-1660," BA thesis, Reed College, May (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Robert Brenner, "The Formation of Economic Policy under James I", BA thesis, Reed College, May (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Carolyn Krysak, "Ralph Cudworth: A Study in Seventeenth Century Epistemology," BA thesis, Reed College, May (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Husaini, S. Waqar - correspondence, C.V., etc. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Husaini, S. Waqar. Muslim Militarism and Islamic Jihad. Working Papers in International Studies, Hoover Institution (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Recommendations, student papers, and search committees
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-255
  - Duplicate honors theses or student papers from classes (not honors theses); version of Theodore Casteel's Ph.D. dissertation (Box 19)
  - Student papers from classes (not honors theses); 1 duplicate honors thesis; 3 papers from Reed College students (Box 20)